### Matthew B. Bowler

Jacksonville Beach, FL 32250 | Phone: 904-351-8487

Portfolio Site: <u>matthewbbowler.com</u> | Email: <u>mbowler03@gmail.com</u> Github: <u>github.com/mbowler03</u> | LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/matthewbowler03</u>

### **SUMMARY**

A seasoned finance professional with over 20 years experience in Mortgage Banking and Community Development with the added technical skills of a FullStack Web Developer. A lifelong learner that is able to bridge any technical gaps and assist companies to lead in an extremely competitive and technology driven world.

### TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

BROWSER BASED TECHNOLOGIES: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, React.js, Bootstrap

SERVER SIDE DEVELOPMENT: MERN Stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js)

**DATABASES:** MySQL (Workbench), MongoDB (ROBO 3T)

**DEPLOYMENT:** Heroku, Git, Github

### **PROJECTS**

Hacker Scrape- <a href="https://github.com/mbowler03/news-scrape">https://github.com/mbowler03/news-scrape</a> and <a href="https://cryptic-forest-75876.herokuapp.com">https://cryptic-forest-75876.herokuapp.com</a>)

This was built with Javascript, Node.js, MongoDB and uses Mongoose, Cheerio, and Axios NPM Packages.

**Google Search-**(<a href="https://github.com/mbowler03/google-book-search">https://google-search-bowler.herokuapp.com/</a>)
This was built with React.js, Express/Node.js, and MongoDB/Mongoose.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Owner, North Florida Healthy Vending

2018 to Present

• Owner of several healthy vending machines located in various private and charter schools in Jacksonville, Florida...

### Loan Officer, BBVA Compass Bank

2018 to 2019

• Loan Officer to four BBVA locations in Jacksonville, Florida

### Senior Loan Officer, Carrington Mortgage Jacksonville, Florida

2015 to 2018

- Closed over 23 million in FHA and VA mortgages in 2016 becoming one of the companies leading producers
- Obtained the promotion of "Senior Loan Officer" during the first month of eligibility by closing an average of over 14 loans per month since date of hire

2013 to 2015

- Specialized in the management of the transportation needs of large retail clients
- Solicited new business obtained from paid sales leads, research, social media, and referrals

## Loan Originator, PHH Mortgage Jacksonville, FL

2011 to 2013

• Originated Mortgage Loans under Private Label Solutions for a variety of companies including: Charles Schwab, Merrill Lynch, E\*Trade, TIAA-Cref, Ameriprise, and Keybank

## **Executive Director, Riverside Avondale Development Organization Jacksonville, FL**

2006 to 2011

- Supervised all business activities, including staff, finances, production, marketing and sales
- Secured a minimum of \$125,000 per year in grants and donations annually
- Increased housing production by 300%, expanded service boundaries, and conducted all predevelopment activities for two future signature projects

# Vice President, Operation New Hope Jacksonville, FL

2000-2006

- Conducted research and repair of property titles including removal and payment of liens and assessed taxes
- Purchased more than sixty properties in the downtown Jacksonville area through grants and lines of credit
- Assisted in raising funds for the organization through grant writing and tax credit submissions
- Sold and marketed all existing housing inventory

### **EDUCATION**

### University of Central Florida Orlando, FL

• Certificate of Completion from 24 Week "Full Stack" Coding BootCamp

## University of North Florida Jacksonville, FL

• Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

### **LANGUAGES**

#### Spanish

• c1 fluency level- certificate obtained from Simon Bolivar Language School Cuenca, Ecuador